<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Links on Gotham Beacon</title>
    <link>https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links on Gotham Beacon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Pass Ultimate</title>
      <link>https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/2019/04/06/game-pass-ultimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/2019/04/06/game-pass-ultimate/</guid>
      <description>I hope Microsoft comes out with this sooner rather than later. I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back since I signed up for Game Pass and the possibility of having an all-encompassing package with Live Gold and Game Pass both for the Xbox and PC is too good to turn down. I prefer to play racing, fighting and sports games on the Xbox, but first-person shooters (and the occasional dabbling with RTS&amp;rsquo;s) are a keyboard and mouse affair for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook Keyboards</title>
      <link>https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/2019/03/28/macbook-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/2019/03/28/macbook-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>They&amp;rsquo;re one of the worst Apple &amp;ldquo;innovations&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve seen since I&amp;rsquo;m a Mac user. Its origin stems from the unwavering obsession with thinness that follows the mantra &amp;ldquo;form over function&amp;rdquo; to the letter. Joanna Stern wrote a brilliant column for The Wall Street Journal debunking this keyboard for the technological fraud it is.
In response, an Apple spokesperson told The Wall Street Journal the following:
 &amp;ldquo;We are aware that a small number of users are having issues with their third-generation butterfly keyboard and for that we are sorry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neil Gaiman’s 8 Rules for Writing</title>
      <link>https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/2018/09/14/neil-gaimans-8-rules-for-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gothambeacon.com/batcave/links/2018/09/14/neil-gaimans-8-rules-for-writing/</guid>
      <description>I plan on getting back to writing over the next couple of weeks. My previous attempts have failed because I always felt like I was missing some guidelines to follow. I also wasn&amp;rsquo;t disciplined enough to keep trying. While browsing the Interwebs, I found Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s list of rules for writing, and it resonated with me.
 Write. Put one word after another. Find the right word, put it down. Finish what you’re writing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>